# **Rory Dow**

# CAD Specialist - Render Artist Designer - Engineer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rory-dow/Location / rory.dow@hotmail.com / +353 851698138

#### Summary

I am a design engineer with 6 years' experience in industry working on aerospace, automotive and industrial waste recycling projects. Currently training to work in software in the future. I have a keen eye for detail and like getting deliverables out on time and right first time. Get in touch if you have work that needs my attention, I'm happy with short or long contracts. I'm part time due to my studies; the format of which can be worked out based on the work, pay negotiable. Appreciate your time.

**Education** 

May 2023 – May 2024 Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (Accredited by the University West of Scotland)

Sep 2012 – Sep 2016 University of Nottingham Nottingham, UK

Masters in Product Design & Manufacturing Engineering

#### **Technical Skillset**

| Programming   | 3D CAD  | Rendering Packages   | 2D Packages  |
|---|---|--|--|
| HTML (proficient) CSS (proficient) JavaScript (competent) Python(competent) | Creo Parametric (native) SolidWorks (proficient) Siemens NX (fluent) Catia V6 (competent) | Keyshot (native)<br>3dsMax (proficient)<br>Blender (capable) | Adobe Photoshop (native) Adobe Illustrator (competent) |

### Skills

| 3D MODELLING   | MARKETING IMAGES  | SYSTEMS DESIGN      | PROTOTYPE   | DRAFTING |
|----------------|-------------------|---------------------|-------------|----------|
| PHOTOREALISTIC | IMAGE EDITING     | REVERSE ENGINEERING | FABRICATION |          |
| RENDERING      | RESEARCH STUDIES  | TECHNICAL DRAWINGS  | DESIGN FOR  |          |
| 3D ANIMATION   | CONCEPT SKETCHING |                     | MANUFACTURE |          |
|                |                   |                     |             |          |

# Work Experience

**2022 - 2023** Turmec Recycling ltd. Drafting Engineer West Meath

My time at Turmec was predominantly spent drafting technical drawings in large numbers for small variant parts for production on site so I received direct feedback for any small errors and learned very quickly to triple check all my work before release. I wrote code to automate some of this design process which massively improved efficiency even just within our small 12-man team of engineers.

**2018 - 2022** Arrival Jet ltd. Design Engineer London

I was approached by a company director at my previous office to join him as the first designer on an experimental electric aerospace project designing large electric drones. I designed the entire first iteration of the vehicle while collaborating with industrial designers. As the project grew, I became a coordinator/manager for my team of 5 design engineers while continuing my role as a designer and engineer. I modeled several high-quality aerodynamic A-surfaces. I was part of the team that built the first full scale prototype, and I followed this by taking ownership and designing several key structural and mechanical systems on the production quality vehicle model.

I specialized in rapidly modelling concept designs for systems and vehicle configurations and then producing high quality renders and animations for concept pitching to 3rd parties and upper management teams during development phases.

Design for manufacture was always at the core of my designs in this role as we had to prove every experimental system out to exacting aerospace standards, after concept were approved.

**2017 - 2018** Arrival ltd. Design Engineer Oxford

As our electric van project moved into a new phase of design preparing for mass manufacture in fully autonomous robo-factories, I moved office from concept design to design for manufacture. I worked closely with analysts to incorporate their data into mechanical and structural designs of the E-van. I worked with a much larger team of contracted automotive engineers and learned a great deal from the Jaguar-Landrover designers when it came to section drawings and detailed engineering drawing standards.

**2016 - 2017** Charge Automotive Itd. Design Engineer London
I was hired straight out of uni into a team of 4 design engineers who were tasked with designing an innovative new electric van. I had no prior automotive experience and jumped comfortably into the deep end designing ground breaking new cooling systems, high voltage housings, composite structural systems, and producing models and renders for management discussion as we developed the product.

#### Certificates/Courses

- Fire Marshall
- Forklift License
- Health and Safety Trained
- High Voltage Competent Person Certificate

## Additional Information/Interests

- I am currently working on building my software development portfolio website.
- My partner and I are expecting our first child to be born in May next year.
- I do a lot of DIY on our home in the country, my partner is an interior designer so there's lots to get right.

References available on request.